倪庆亮 Yí Qìng Liàng Pukou District, Nanjing City, Jiangsu Province Male, Han 1982.10

https://github.com/downloads/walkthetalk/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/yi-qingliang-62a026aa https://niqingliang2003.wordpress.com/

niqingliang2003@gmail.com

1 +8615996246393

Self Assessment

More than 12 years experience worked in product R&D department of Ether / SDH transmission equipment. Very adaptable and Good at leaning. Diligent; with sureness; responsible; everytime fulfil my duties to my own work. Patient; have holding capacity to pressure and setback.

Experienced on GNU/Linux, from bootloader, kernel/driver, to application, all are covered. Experienced on FPGA development, focused on Image processing and Motor control.

Work Experience

2012 today

Nanjing Jilong Optical Communication Co., Ltd R&D Nanjing Manager

Build up Tech Platform based on GNU/Linux;

Responsible for new staff technical training;

Presided over the design and development of the next generation splicing control system. Through motor controlling, image processing, arc controlling, implement fusion splicing, heating, arc adjustment, system testing, dust checking, auto focusing, etc.

tech involved: state machine, socket communication, json message, xml configuration, image processing, video recording, etc. FPGA is responsible for image sampling, format converting, image scaling, image overlaying, motor controlling, etc.

Dev Env: Xilinx Vivado, Archlinux, gitlab, poky(yocto), opencv, boost, TEXlive, Qt, maxima, android studio.

Programming Language: verilog, python, Makefile, ConTEXt, C++11, C, bash, lua Hardware Platform: arm, s3c6410, zynq7020

2010 ~ 2012 Insigma Iot BU Hangzhou

- Responsible for pre-research and construction of software department infrastructure;
- Participate in the overall design of the software platform;
- Responsible for the design and development of the low-level software platform;
- Research and use of open source software / projects, design and development of related supporting tools;
- Responsible for some recruitment and technical training;
- As SA735 product development representative, responsible for its software development and release management;
- Participate SN6500 product software design and development;
- Responsible for the data center's preliminary research work, including hardware selection, distributed file system, distributed database.

Development environment is mainly Linux and C/C++. Development work including but not limited to:

- Embedded OS build system optimus (based on yocto) Mainly in order to solve the problem of product differentiation, one platform supporting multiple products.
- GUI compiling tool: Tai Chi diagram (based on wxPython), providing a GUI to display dependencies between packages, and executing recursive compilation.
- Dual redundancy backup system design and development (including supporting tool).
- Process Execution Model, Driver framework (mainly used for seamless switching between the user mode and kernel mode) Process and equipment management module, FPGAs/CPLDs Loading module.
- mm/md used under GNU/Linux (same command used in uboot).
- scripts used to generate UBIFS image.
- p2020/mpc8315 (freescale/powerpc) related bsp dev.
- ...

2009 ~ 2010 NSN NGMGW Hangzhou team leader of TDM group

Responsible for TDM related service, including business needs analysis, writing related documents and software design and development, e.g. SDH/PDH configuration management, clock management, and the corresponding redundancy, etc.

2007 ~ 2009 UT Starcom ONS Hangzhou SW engineer

mainly woring for product NR40K:

- low-order XC chip research and development;
- development of XC board, hybrid fiber board;
- development of hot-backup, SSF, MAPS;
- development and maintenance of: configuration management, algorithm module;
- interrupt management, timer managment;

Development environment: windows/vxworks, C/C++.

2005 ~ 2006 HarbourNetworks R&D switch product line Beijing SW engineer

mainly working on product BH68 series switcher:

Responsible for development of QoS/ACL, including maintenance of application/driver, new requirement of MassACL, IPv6, fucntion testing of new chip, firebolt/easyridar from broadcom.

Responsible for development and maintenance of DHCP module.

Development environment: windows/vxworks, C/C++.

Education

 $2004 \sim 2007$ Master Xidian University Xi' an Computer science and technology

2000 \sim 2004 **Bachelor** Xidian University Xi' an Computer science and technology

Language

English CET-6